# R. EOGHAN HULBERT

(401) 203-5038 | Eoghan@Hulbert.info | Woonsocket, RI 02895 - Relocating to Chandler, AZ

#### **CAREER GOAL**

Seeking long-term opportunities for technical development in information systems roles. The ideal roles would be associate level or above for Systems Analyst or Business Analyst; entry level for Automation Analyst or Systems Engineer. My 3-year goal is to gain new experience in enterprise systems and tools to meet qualifications for more in-depth technical roles.

## **EXPERIENCE**

### **CSR II: CONSUMER DATA PROTECTION - MetLife**

Dec 2019 to Present

- Provided website technical expertise and admin support for providers, benefits administrators and policyholders
- Elected as team ambassador for the MetLife Way leadership program to actively promote, train, and achieve organization goals and values within department
- Evaluated and participated in Root Cause Problem Solving initiative projects, providing resolutions and efficiencies for enhancing core operations, communication and workflow development
- Cross-trained in multiple departments, acted as resource and information liaison, and job coach to assist peers with complex problem solving, admin, and professional development
- Q1 2020 CSR Metrics Ranking: Top 50% of Global Customer Service, Top 25% of Web Support, Top 20% of Customer Data Protection

### ASSOCIATE FINANCIAL SYSTEMS ANALYST - Amica Mutual Insurance

Sept 2018 to July 2019

- Provided technical expertise and mediation between accounting, external departments and vendor software distributors by building direct relationships with department managers and leads
- Analyzed development opportunities for current system enhancements and integrations to increase efficiency and promote task automations to meet business needs
- Managed mid to high-level accounting project portfolio from requirements gathering to delivery with an overall task success rate of 98% and minimal oversight
- Reduced wasted effort in Treasury by 58% annually with the development of custom automated systems to handle monthly bank reconciliation data for premium reimbursements

# **COLLECTIONS SERVICES REP I - Mapfre Insurance USA**

May 2017 to July 2018

- Successfully managed \$35,000 collections portfolio with an average of 300 policies across multiple states and policy types, including high-risk accounts
- Proprietor of the national lines of business accounts in collections and trained new personnel in national policies and procedures as backup representatives
- Spearheaded multiple collections workflow analysis projects resulting in a 5% increase of premium recovery in national LOB from 2017 and reduction in third party commission payments by 30%
- Reduced wasted effort in initial policy research by 348 hours per person annually by implementing new collections criteria based on trends in repayment data analysis

# R. EOGHAN HULBERT

(401) 203-5038 | Eoghan@Hulbert.info | Woonsocket, RI 02895 - Relocating to Chandler, AZ

#### **EXPERIENCE CONTINUED**

# **SUPPORT SERVICES REP I - Mapfre Insurance USA**

Nov 2015 to May 2017

- Identified, scanned and indexed an average of 900 incoming claims documents into business databases daily, exceeding 95% accuracy rate guidelines
- Collaborated in the Greater Place to Work Committee, hosted department events, and participated in continuing insurance education training with The Institutes
- Restructured document storage and destruction procedures reducing improper handling incidents to 0% and strengthened SEC and HIPAA regulatory compliance within backend operations

#### **EDUCATION**

#### SOUTHERN NEW HAMPSHIRE UNIVERSITY

**B.A.** Information Technology

Graduated: 12/2017

GPA: 3.25

**Senior Project:** Developed functional prototype web application based on a real-world business problem by drafting project management plans with given requirements and scope, adhering to project timelines, and utilizing multiple programming languages to produce deliverables

## **SKILLS**

# **S**OFT

Admin, Liability Insurance, Operations, Project Management, Requirements Gathering and Analysis, Root Cause Problem Solving, Time Management

### **TECHNICAL**

Data Analysis, Database Management, Java, JavaScript, MS Server, Python, SQL, Systems Analysis and Design, Technical Writing, Usability Testing, VBA, Web App Development

# Courses

- 7 Habits of Highly Effective People Amica Insurance 2018
- Introduction to Property & Casualty Insurance The Institutes 2017

# **ADDITIONAL**

LINKEDIN: LinkedIn.com/in/EHulbert

**Website:** Eoghan.Hulbert.info